[Music]
hi and welcome to this session on what's
new in financial management in this
session we'll take a closer look at the
GL account revaluation or currency code
on GL if you want my name is Brian
Nelson I'm a manager with the business
Central
team and for general ledger it has been
a top request that we put
original uh currency code uh on the
entries uh it's been there for 5 years
or more it has probably more than 500
votes and we've thought about it for a
long time and in this release uh you
will get original currency code on GL
entry
you will also be able to control the
posting of currencies to G which
currencies you want to allow posting for
and then whether you want
revaluation uh to happen on a specific
GL account and of course we have added a
batch job that will create adjustment
entries to revalue a balance in G but
let's take a a little closer look at the
feature you need to turn it on in
feature management it's called enable a
use of GL currency
revaluation so in my
company we go to chart of
accounts I've created a a subset in in
this view you can see that I created a
new account to keep track of a loan that
I taken in
Euros um and there are also some like I
take the loan it goes into my bank
account when I do the adjustments that
you will see soon they need to go to uh
realized gains and losses or on realized
gains and losses uh in this case if it's
a monetary asset that I keep track
of so to register the loan we post some
journal entries I've already created
those so to register the transaction I
have these two lines I get my loan in
two
parts um it I posted beginning of
January I picked the currency rate uh
currency code which is zero and I post
it to my bank you can see that I get a
small part 10,000 that gets converted
into 15,000 in local currency US dollar
and I just post to the bank so let's
just post
this and we can go back to our chart of
accounts and you can see that I have a
liability of 150,000 in Us
doll but I've taken the loan in Euros at
the end of February for example when I I
do uh want to create a financial
statement the exchange rate has changed
slightly and I want that to be reflected
on in this liabilities
account before I would have to keep
track of it in a spreadsheet do some
journal entries post them to to make
these adjustments that was Compass some
now we've given you a help in creating
those entries in this case we will pick
a journal so we can hold the adjustments
end of February we'll just focus on this
account uh we don't have to worry about
uh currencies in this scenario we only
posted one currency and we get um an
adjustment so let's quickly take a look
at that
adjustment we have one adjustment I'll
just show
you currencies and we're picking at
Euro we're picking the rates and in end
of February the rate has gone from 15
to4 so we are experiencing a a gain here
because we owe less uh on this loan so
we expect that to to to be reflected in
this journal
posting so um we're good it has the
information and we'll just post it no
need to make adjustments in this
case and we can see did immediately when
you post it the loan is now 140,000
reflecting the fact that the exchange
rate has gone down a bit and the uh the
adjustment has been posted just as I
specified in the setup that it goes to
unrealized gains and I can continue that
if we look at the entries
here you can see that this is the entry
I made a a mistake so I had to uh
reverse it but there's only one
uh entry for adjustment because we
adjust the balance per currency it's not
adjustment for each of the
entries so in the second scenario we'll
we'll look at the setup
and this will the setup will allow us to
post to multiple currencies to the same
GL account and you can still do
revaluation um and we'll we'll just take
a look at at what is the output of that
and then we can dig into what are the
differences between this and the normal
curreny exchange rate
adjustments but let's dig a little
deeper into the scenario so we are back
to the loan was posted in January
adjusted in February on this account but
uh if we go into the
account you can see at the fast tab
here that I have selected multiple
currencies that means that I will allow
multiple currency transactions to be
posted to this account and that's of
course for demo
purposes uh I would probably recommend
that you always pick same currency and
then you pick uh a
currency in in the currency code field
if you have set it up to have multiple
currencies you can go to the related
table Source currencies and in there you
can just specify which other or which
multiple currencies will you
allow in this case I also allow Canadian
dollars I can also select that I will
only allow u local currency so I don't
get any transaction it's it's just an
option that I that I have and I can
select to have blank which means that
any currency goes just standard business
uh Central Behavior I can toggle this
one this parameter and say tell the
system that I want revaluation to happen
for this GL account and when it happens
I want the adjustment entries to post to
the
unrealized um gains and losses account
that is set up on the currency but I
want like they are both unrealized and
realized gains and losses account in
this case I picked the unrealized
because it's a monetary asset that I'm
tracking so that's the setup uh and
basically all you need to to to know
about um
revaluation in this case we allowed
multiple currencies so let's post
multiple
currencies so I've taken a new loan uh
this time in Canadian dollars I post to
the same account because I set it up to
allow uh multiple currencies to be
posted to it I pick Canadian dollars I
have some amounts in this case I will
also do it in a as a two-part uh
transaction a small part and a little
bigger part I post to my bank account
the rate for Canadian dollars
um they go in the opposite direction of
Euros Euros was was going down so I I
get gains Canadian dollars go a little
up as you can see here they go from uh
100 to 80 to 100 to 85 and 90 in March
so they go in opposite direction so we
are expecting gains to be posted to
Euros or four Euros and losses to be
posted for can Ian dollars but let's
just post this uh transaction it's in
January just so we have some nice
numbers and we can go back to our chart
of
accounts and we look at this
subset so now we
posted uh a loan in Euro and a loan in
Canadian dollars we adjusted the Euro
loan but we didn't adjust the Canadian
dollar loan it's still here um we have
the loan here if I click here and search
for the
entries you can see that after I posted
the gains and losses for the EUR loan I
only posted the transaction so we need
to make the the same adjustment for
Canadian dollars to this account and
same as before you just run the badge
job you pick a
journal and you pick the account you
could pick uh Canadian dollars but since
the balance for euros is already
adjusted nothing will happen if you also
include Canadian dollars so we'll just
leave it blank and we'll get one line in
our Journal so let's take a look at
that so we have an
adjustment it is just for the Canadian
dollars and that's it went from 100 to
80 to 100 to 85 so we are we are we'll
have a small loss of 5,000 uh for
Canadian dollars here and we'll just
post
it and then we'll go back to child of
accounts and you can see the adjustments
has has been
made uh and and it has been posted to
the losses account so you can have
multiple currencies we will post an
adjustment for each of the
currencies uh that are uh posted to in
in a GL account and you'll be able to
set it up per account you'll be able to
control the currencies you'll be able to
control if revaluation is going to
happen and of course in this case we
only selected this account it wouldn't
make any sense to allow GL revaluation
for bank accounts because revaluation is
done for bank accounts for customers and
vendors so it the same goes with your
account paybl and account receivables
account uh you don't do adjustments for
those because you have the standard
currency exchange rate batch job to do
that uh balance the difference is
important to understand uh we make one
adjustment per currency for the the
balance uh in in that GL account when
you're running adjustments for customers
and vendors you are doing it per
customer and vendor and even with the
new one
the new um batch job that you can turn
on in feature management let's just take
a a brief look at
that go to
currencies and in here from here you can
run the job this is a separate job that
is done for customers vendors and now
also employees and uh bank
accounts but they will do it per
customer and vendor for bank accounts we
are still adjusting the uh the
balance um you can now adjust per entry
so it's not just per customer or per
vendor but it's per each of these
customer and vendor LED entries for the
GL revaluation it is just an adjustment
per Bal adjustment per balance per
currency so it there's a there's a
difference there so when you start using
this new feature with GL revaluation you
need to think about does that meet your
reporting requirement if you need to
keep track of very detailed adjustments
to each transaction I would recommend
that you use customers and vendors for
that uh like a customer or a vendor
account to do that if you just need to
keep track of of the full balance you
can use GL
revaluation so with that uh I want you
to thank you for watching this session
if you have
feedback uh go to BC ideas and submit
ideas or vote for some of the existing
ideas this new feature came from BC
ideas we already had it in the backlog
but the votes we got there which is more
than 500 came from BC ERS uh and was the
one that triggered us to uh to add it to
this release thank you for joining the
session